# PITHAYUTH (WILL) CHARNSETHIKUL

pithayuth.me | linkedin.com/pithayuth | charnset@usc.edu

### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research focuses on understanding human behaviors and perception around cybersecurity through variety of data such as client (i.e., user study), system, and social media. The goal is to apply my findings by integrating my expertise in machine learning, specifically in NLP, and the field of security to enhance users' online security and privacy experiences.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Southern California, Ph.D., Computer Science

Advisors: Jelena Mirkovic

Los Angeles, California 2021-present

University of Southern California, M.S., Computer Science

Specialization: Computer Networks

Los Angeles, California

2019-2021

**Kasetsart University, B.Eng., Computer Engineering** 

Bangkok, Thailand 2014-2018

**ACADEMIC EXPERIENCES** 

### **Graduate Research Assistant**

August 2021-Present

USC Information Sciences Institute (ISI), STEEL: Security Research Lab

Marina Del Rey, California

- Privacy Setting: conduct a user study that investigates how social media users adjust their default privacy settings.
- Anti-Scam: develop a dialogue system that not only engages with scammers but also extracts their information.

### **Student Worker, Research**

August 2019-May 2021

USC Information Sciences Institute (ISI), STEEL: Security Research Lab

Marina Del Rey, California

- Venmo: build a neural classifier that categorizes Venmo public transactions into multiple sensitive classes.
- **Cloud Misbehavior**: identify which /24 network prefixes are "cloud", then quantify the amount of bad traffic originated from these networks.
- DDoS Detection: implement various anomaly detection approaches and evaluate them with the captured traffic.

Directed Research August 2020–May 2021

Mentor: John Heidemann Remote

• **DNS latency**: modify DNS servers to solicit TCP from selected clients, allowing us to determine RTTs.

Teaching Assistant January 2023-Present

USC Viterbi Department of Computer Science

Amazon, SCOT-IPC: Specialized Selection

Los Angeles, California

- CSCI 430: Introduction to Computer and Network Security, Fall 2023, Instructor: Jelena Mirkovic
- CSCI 567: Machine learning, Spring 2023, Instructor: Yan Liu

### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCES**

# **Applied Scientist Intern**

May 2023-August 2023

Bellevue, Washington

- Analyze customer's search data and calculate basket (i.e., online shopping cart) abandonment probability.
- Comprehensively investigate what drive basket abandonment, e.g., basket size, free shipping threshold, etc.
- Develop a neural network model that predicts the basket abandonment probability given an input of customer basket.

Technical Intern II June 2022-August 2022

AT&T Labs Research, Mentor: Anestis Karasaridis

Remote

- DNS data collection and analysis, specifically for DNS-over-TLS (DoT) and DNS-over-HTTPS (DoH).
  - Add DNS source code (PowerDNS dnsdist) to extract session ID and user-agent from DoT/DoH queries and create a data pipeline to transfer and enrich data between Azure environment and Snowflake.
  - Analyze collected data on Azure Databricks.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- GLOBECOMM 2022: AMON-SENSS: Scalable and Accurate Detection of Volumetric DDoS Attacks at ISPs; Rajat Tandon,
   Pithayuth Charnsethikul, Michalis Kallitsis, Jelena Mirkovic
- PETS2022: I know what you did on Venmo: Discovering privacy leaks in mobile social payments; Rajat Tandon, Pithayuth
   Charnsethikul, Ishank Arora, Dhiraj Murthy, Jelena Mirkovic
   Acceptance Rate: 21.02% (33/157)
- PAM2022: Old but Gold: Prospecting TCP to Engineer and Live Monitor DNS Anycast; Giovane C. M. Moura, John Heidemann, Wes Hardaker, Pithayuth Charnsethikul, Jeroen Bulten, João M. Ceron and Cristian Hesselman Best Paper Award
- CloudNet2020: Quantifying Cloud Misbehavior; Rajat Tandon, Jelena Mirkovic, Pithayuth Charnsethikul

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Languages**: Python, C, C++, Bash, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Typescript, SQL, JAVA, Perl, Łargen Frameworks: scikit-learn, PyTorch, Torch, TensorFlow, Keras, Huggingface, Angular, Node.js, Spark

Packages and Tools: NumPy, Pandas, SciPy, Git, Docker, MySQL

Platforms: Linux, macOS, Windows, Arduino, Raspberry, GCP, Azure, AWS

Networking: tcpdump, Wireshark, Nmap, Knot DNS, dnsdist

### **GRADUATE COURSEWORK**

Advanced Analysis of Algorithms, Applied Cryptography, Foundations of Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Advanced Natural Language Processing, Robustness and Generalization in Natural Language Processing, Advanced Operating Systems, Advanced Computer Networking, Security Systems

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Deep Learning Specialization by DeepLearning.Al, Coursera

#### REFERENCES

- Jelena Mirkovic, Research Associate Professor, USC ISI, mirkovic@isi.edu
- · Genevieve Bartlett, Senior Computer Scientist, USC ISI, bartlett@isi.edu